New York State Defenders Association (NYSDA); Records apap110
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
New York State Defenders Association Records
1975-1998
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
New York State Defenders Association
apap110
12.0 cubic ft.
The collection contains photocopied news clippings related to the death penalty, amassed by the New York State Defenders Association.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives by the New York State Defenders Association 2001 February
Biographical History
The New York State Defenders Association (NYSDA), a not-for-profit, membership organization, has been providing support to New York's criminal defense community since 1967. Its mission is to improve the quality and scope of publicly supported legal representation to low income people. NYSDA is the largest criminal defense bar association in New York and among the first statewide defense organizations to be established in the country. Membership is open to lawyers, people in the public defense client community, defense team members, such as sentencing specialists, and others committed to improving the quality of publicly supported criminal defense.
All information in this Biographical History was taken from the New York State Defenders Association website. (Accessed 11 October 2004).
Scope and Contents
The collection is composed solely of photocopied news clippings related to the death penalty. The news clippings were accumulated by the New York State Defenders Association from the New York State Newspaper Clippings Service and arranged in binders. All news clippings were photocopied before being deposited in the Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection has no series. It is arranged chronologically.
Death Penalty; Criminal Justice and Prisons; Capital punishment--New York (State); Criminal law--New York (State); Executions and executioners--New York (State); Clippings; New York State Defenders Association
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1975 April-1982 (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 1)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1982 May-1983 February (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 2)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1983 February-1984 January (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 3)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1984 February-March (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 4)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1984 April-June (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 5)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1984 July-1985 February (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 6)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1985 February-May (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 7)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1985 June-1986 January (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 8)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1986 February-March (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 9)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1986 April-July (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 10)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1986 August-1987 February (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 11)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1987 March-December (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 12)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1988 January-April (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 13)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1988 May-June (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 14)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1988 July-September (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 15)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1988 October (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 16)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1988 November-December (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 17)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1989 January-February (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 18)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1989 February (Box 1 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 19)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1989 March (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 1)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1989 March (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 2)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1989 March (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 3)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1989 March (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 4)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1989 April (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 5)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1989 May (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 6)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1989 May (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 7)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1989 June (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 8)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1989 July 1989-November (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 9)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1989 December-1990 January (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 10)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1990 February (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 11)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1990 March (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 12)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1990 March-April (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 13)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1990 April-September (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 14)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1990 June-July (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 15)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1990 August-September (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 16)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1990 October (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 17)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1990 November (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 18)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1990 December (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 19)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1991 January-February (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 20)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1991 March (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 21)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1991 April (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 22)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1991 May (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 23)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1991 June (Box 2 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 24)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1991 July (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 1)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1991 August (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 2)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1991 September-November (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 3)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1991 December-1992 February (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 4)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1992 March (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 5)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1992 April (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 6)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1992 May (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 7)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1992 May (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 8)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1992 June (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 9)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1992 June (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 10)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1992 July (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 11)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1992 August-September (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 12)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1992 September (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 13)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1992 October (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 14)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1992 October (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 15)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1992 November (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 16)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1992 December-1993 January (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 17)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1993 January-February (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 18)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1993 March (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 19)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1993 April (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 20)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1993 May (Box 3 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 21)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1993 June (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 1)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1993 June (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 2)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1993 July (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 3)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1993 August-September (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 4)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1993 October (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 5)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1993 October (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 6)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1993 October (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 7)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1993 November (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 8)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1993 December (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 9)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 January (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 10)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 January (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 11)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 January (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 12)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 January (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 13)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 February (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 14)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 February (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 15)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 March (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 16)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 March (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 17)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 March (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 18)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 April (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 19)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 April (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 20)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 April (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 21)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 April (Box 4 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 22)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 May (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 1)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 May (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 2)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 June (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 3)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 June (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 4)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 July (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 5)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 July (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 6)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 July (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 7)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 July (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 8)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 August (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 9)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 August-September (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 10)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 September (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 11)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 September (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 12)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 October 1-12 (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 13)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 October 12-16 (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 14)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 October 16-22 (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 15)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 October 22-27 (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 16)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 October 27-31 (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 17)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 November 1 (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 18)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 November 3 (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 19)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 November 4 (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 20)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 November 6 (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 21)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 November 7 (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 22)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 November 10 (Box 5 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 23)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 November 11-14 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 1)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 November 14-18 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 2)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 November 18-23 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 3)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 November 24-30 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 4)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 December 1-9 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 5)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 December 10-26 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 6)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1994 December 26-31 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 7)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 January (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 8)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 January (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 9)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 January 6-9 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 10)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 January 9-11 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 11)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 January 12-13 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 12)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 January 14-19 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 13)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 January 19-22 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 14)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 January 23-26 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 15)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 January 26-31 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 16)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 February 1-9 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 17)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 February 10-14 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 18)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 February 14-16 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 19)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 February 16 (Box 6 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 20)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 February 17-22 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 1)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 February 22-23 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 2)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 February 23-26 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 3)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 February 26-28 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 4)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 February 28 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 5)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 March 1-3 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 6)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 March 3-7 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 7)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 March 7-11 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 8)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 March 11-15 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 9)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 March 15-20 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 10)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 March 20-24 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 11)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 March 24-31 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 12)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 April 1-9 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 13)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 April 9-17 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 14)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 April 17-24 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 15)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 April 24-May 5 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 16)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 May 5-25 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 17)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 May 25-June 7 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 18)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 June 7-30 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 19)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 July 1-11 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 20)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 July 11-18 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 21)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 July 18-25 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 22)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 July 25-August 22 (Box 7 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 23)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 August 22-September 27 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 1)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 October (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 2)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 November 1-15 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 3)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 November 15-23 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 4)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 November 24-30 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 5)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 December 1-14 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 6)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 December 14-24 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 7)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1995 December 24-1996 January 7 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 8)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 January 7-18 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 9)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 January 18-31 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 10)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 February 1-16 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 11)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 February 16-29 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 12)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 March 1-16 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 13)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 March 16-21 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 14)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 March 21-25 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 15)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 March 25-29 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 16)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 March 29-April 5 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 17)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 April 5-15 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 18)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 April 15-21 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 19)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 April 21-May 5 (Box 8 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 20)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 May 5-26 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 1)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 May 25-June 5 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 2)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 June 5-14 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 3)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 June 14-30 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 4)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 July-December (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 5)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 December 12-31 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 6)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 August 1-15 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 7)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 August 15-31 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 8)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 September 1-11 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 9)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 September 11-26 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 10)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 September 26-October 5 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 11)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 October 5-16 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 12)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 October 16-31 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 13)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 November 1-13 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 14)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 November 13-21 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 15)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 November 21-December 3 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 16)
- Death Penalty, News Clippings, 1996 December 3-13 (Box 9 (New York State Defenders Association Records), Folder 17)